Guide to the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station records, 1859-2008
New York State Agricultural Experiment Station records, 1859-2008
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State Agricultural Experiment Station records, 1859-2008.
22-1-44
New York State Agricultural Experiment Station.
133.3 cubic ft.
Letters, photographs, clippings, drawings, meeting minutes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Minutes of meetings of the Board of Control and Reports of the Director; correspondence files; sketches, photographs and other materials concerning staff members; clippings relating to the experiment station, milk production and testing, and agricultural problems in New York State. Clippings; certificates from the Universal Exposition of 1900 and the United States Exposition of 1904; drawings of the Director's residence; and memorabilia from the centennial celebration of the station, 1981-1982. The bulk of the collection is from the directorship of Whitman H. Jordan, 1896-1921. Two kits for the counting of bacteria in milk, and the first watchman's clock used at Geneva. Also, records for the years 1859-1957; and an award to the Station for exhibits at the Pan American Exhibition, 1895-1920.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Minutes of meetings of the Board of Control and Reports of the Director which include fiscal reports and some operating reports after 1892; extensive correspondence files; sketches, photographs and other biographical materials concerning staff members; scrapbooks of clippings relating to the experiment station, milk production and testing, and agricultural problems in New York State. Also, additional clippings; lithographed certificates from the Universal Exposition of 1900 and the United States Exposition of 1904; drawings of the Director's residence; and memorabilia from the centennial celebration of the station, 1981-1982. The records throw considerable light on the beginnings of the Experiment Station, the setting up of its Board of Control, the interest in its activities by individual and organized farmers, the discussions over conflicting operating and experimental plans, the adoption of general policies, and the aims of various directors. The bulk of the collection is from the directorship of Whitman H. Jordan, 1896-1921. Two kits for the counting of bacteria in milk, and the first watchman's clock used at Geneva. Also, records for the years 1859-1957; and an award to the Station for exhibits at the Pan American Exhibition, 1895-1920.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State Agricultural Experiment Station.; Jordan, Whitman H. (Whitman Howard), 1851-1931.
Subjects:
Agricultural experiment stations--New York (State)--Geneva.; Agriculture--Study and teaching; Agriculture and state.; Agriculture--Research.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Additional material and digital versions can be found online here: http://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/359
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collections 21-12-1651 and 21-12-76.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Subject Files
Series II. Departments and Centers
Series III. Buildings
Series IV. Centennial and Other Anniversaries
Series V. Awards and Diplomas
Series VI. Films and Videos
Series VII. Photographs/Slides
Series VIII. Publications/Publicity
Series IX. Conferences, Projects, Symposiums
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Subject Files
- Biographical materials (done by Hedrick) arranged alphabetically (Box 90)
- Interview Tape: Donald W. Barton (Box 120)
- Interview Tape: (Box 120)
  - Rosaleen Mazur, Side A
  - Nelson Shaulis, Side B
- Documentation of Employees, 1942-1953 (Box 125, Folder 13-19)
- Biographical Documentation of NYSAES Staff- A-G, 1940s-1950s (Box 136, Folder 3)
- Biographical Documentation of NYSAES Staff - H-L, 1940s-1950s (Box 136, Folder 4)
- Biographical Documentation of NYSAES Staff - O-Z, 1940s-1950s (Box 136, Folder 5)
- Biographical Documentation of NYSAES Non-Professional Staff - A-Z, 1940s-1950s (Box 136, Folder 6)
- Rev. James Lawson - Created Wax Fruit Model, 1960s (Box 136, Folder 16)
- Chronological disbounded letter books, 1880-[1889-1893] (Box 1)
- Alpha A-G, 1901 (Box 2)
- H-S, 1901 (Box 3)
- S-Z, A-CL, 1901-1902 (Box 4)
- Coa-Kz, 1902 (Box 5)
- La-W, 1902 (Box 6)
- Wn-Z, A-Cz, 1902-1903 (Box 7)
- Cz-Lz, 1903 (Box 8)
- Lz-Sz, 1903 (Box 9)
- Ta-Z, 1903-1904 (Box 10)
- Dan-Lu, 1904 (Box 11)
- Mc-W, 1904 (Box 12)
- Wi-Z, A-Cz, 1904-1905 (Box 13)
- Dr-Hz, 1905 (Box 14)
- Ja-Sn, 1905 (Box 15)
- Sm-Z, A-Ag, 1905-1906 (Box 16)
- Ba-Dz, 1906 (Box 17)
- Ea-Hg, 1906 (Box 18)
- Ja-Q, 1906 (Box 19)
- 0-Z, 1906 (Box 20)
- A-Ez, 1907 (Box 21)
- Fa-Oz, 1907 (Box 22)
- P-Z, 1907 (Box 23)
- A-K (old folders not in letterbook), 1907 (Box 24)
- Correspondence to N.O. Booth - Early Grape Breeder, 1908 (Box 135, Folder 5)
- K-Z, A-l (Auditing Committee Minutes, Budgets), 1907, 1908, 1896-1902 (Box 25)
- H-M (Box 26)
- M-T, 1908 (Box 27)
- T-Z, Special letters, 1908 (Box 28)
- A-Ev, 1908 (Box 29)
- Ev-G, A-B, 1908-1909 (Box 30)
- B-E, 1909 (Box 31)
- F-H, 1909 (Box 32)
- Ja-P, 1909 (Box 33)
- P-T, 1909 (Box 34)
- T-Z, A, 1909-1910 (Box 35)
- B-C, 1910 (Box 36)
- C-Fz, 1910 (Box 37)
- Ga-Ke, 1910 (Box 38)
- Ka-Son, 1910 (Box 39)
- La-W, 1910 (Box 40)
- W-Z, A-B, 1910-1911 (Box 41)
- B-Dz, 1911 (Box 42)
- E-H, 1911 (Box 43)
- H-Ly, 1911 (Box 44)
- Ma-Pe, 1911 (Box 45)
- Pe-Si, 1911 (Box 46)
- Sik-Tz, 1911 (Box 47)
- U-Z, 1911 (Box 48)
- A-By, 1912 (Box 49)
- C-F, 1912 (Box 50)
- G-J, 1912 (Box 51)
- K-N, 1912 (Box 52)
- N-S, 1912 (Box 53)
- Unprocessed (Box 54)
- W-Z, A-B, 1912-1913 (Box 55)
- B-E, 1913 (Box 56)
- E-H, 1913 (Box 57)
- H-M, 1913 (Box 58)
- M-S, 1913 (Box 59)
- S-W, 1913 (Box 60)
- W-Miscellaneous, A-B, 1913-1914 (Box 61)
- B-E, 1914 (Box 62)
- E-H, 1914 (Box 63)
- H-M, 1914 (Box 64)
- N-S, 1914 (Box 65)
- S-Z, 1914 (Box 66)
- Miscellaneous, A-F, 1914-1915 (Box 67)
- G-N, 1915 (Box 68)
- O-Miscellaneous, 1915 (Box 69)
- A-K, 1916 (Box 70)
- L-Miscellaneous, 1916 (Box 71)
- Miscellaneous, A-F, 1916-1917 (Box 72)
- G-Q, 1917 (Box 73)
- R-Z, A-D, 1917-1918 (Box 74)
- E-Miscellaneous, 1918 (Box 75)
- A-Z, 1918-1919 (mixed) (Box 76)
- A-S, 1919 (Box 77)
- T-Miscellaneous, A-R, 1919, 1920 (Box 78)
- S-Miscellaneous, A-K, 1920-1921 (Box 79)
- L-Z, A-K, 1920-1921 (mixed),1921 (Box 80)
- L-Z, A-N, 1921-1922 (Box 81)
- M-Z, A-E, 1922, 1922-1923 (mixed) (Box 82)
- F-Z, A-D, 1922-1923, 1923 (mixed) (Box 83)
- E-Miscellaneous, 1923 (Box 84)
- A-Z, Miscellaneous, 1924 (Box 85)
- Miscellaneous, A-Z, 1924-1925 (Box 86)
- A-Z, Miscellaneous, 1926-1927 (Box 87)
- Lucket correspondence and press releases, S-T, 1928-1929, 1908 (Box 88)
- Unprocessed (Box 89)
- Record book, 1880-1901 (Box 91)
- Scrapbooks of clippings concerning Dairy cows, 1870-1875 (Box 91)
- Experiment station, 1880-1885 (Box 91)
- Agricultural subjects, 1875-1887 (Box 91)
- Diseases of Plants,Experiments, 1884 (Box 91)
- Correspondence between Geneva Experiment Station and New York State College of Agriculture, 1920-1923 (Box 92)
- Dr. Heinicke (Box 92)
- "Finger Lakes Topics" Booklet, 1933 (Box 94)
- 3 Museum Items
  - First Watchman's Clock Used at the Station, 1916 (Box 95)
  - Kits Made in Germany and Japan for Breed Method of Counting Bacteria in Milk, 1916 (Box 95)
  - Technical Bulletin by NYAES, "Counting Bacteria By Means of the Microscope", 1916 (Box 95)
- A Laboratory Manual in Systematic Pomology - Hedrick, not dated (Box 96)
- 9 Accession Books, 1922-1924 (Box 96)
- 6 Accession Records Books, 1941-1976 (Box 96)
- Notebook of T.S. Hubbard Presented to the Experiment Station - Mrs. Percival Parrott, 1945 (Box 96)
- The Geneva Times, October 4, 1957 (Box 97)
- Notes and Harvest Records, 1914-1957 (Box 97)
- 4 Books of Records and Notes, 1896-1904 (Box 97)
- Framed Geneva Gazette Article, "Government Flowers in Geneva,", September 29, 1893 (Box 98)
- Dr. E. Lewis Sturtevant's Correspondence, 1882 (Box 98)
- Correspondence with the Director of the Experiment Station, 1889 (Box 98)
- Record Book on Gas, Oil, Automotive expenses, 1939-1941 (Box 98)
- Record Book Detailing Percentages of Chemicals Present, 1910 (Box 98)
- Summary of Inventory, 1937-1939 (Box 98)
- Produce Account by Agricultural Experiment Station - documents produce sold from May 1924 - July 1934, 1924-1934 (Box 99)
- Record Books of 3 Apple Orchards (Dawley, Vanalstyne, Wood), 1903-1914 (Box 100)
- Record Books of Various Orchards of Peaches, Apples, Grapes, Berries, Pears, Plums, 1893-1903 (Box 101)
- Record Books of Various Orchards of Peaches, Apples, Grapes, Pears, Plums, Small Fruits, 1894-1903 (Box 102)
- Record Books of Various Orchards of Peaches, Apricots, Grapes, Pears, Plums, Small Fruits, Vegetables, 1892-1903 (Box 103)
- Record Books of Various Orchards of Peaches, Apples, Currants, Grapes, Stone Fruits, Small Fruits, 1893-1903 (Box 104)
- Correspondence Regarding the Hitchings Orchard; Hitchings Orchard Background Material; Apple Experiment Notes; Plums - Copies of Foreign Publications; Correspondence Regarding Plums, 1830-1915 (Box 105)
- General Fruit Bleeding Record, 1928 (Box 106)
- Correspondence, 1910-1920 (Box 106)
- Auchter Orchard Background Material, 1905-1910 (Box 107)
- Winery Pamphlets; Blank Weekly Calendar, 1965-1988 (Box 107)
- Soil Studies, 1904-1905 (Box 107)
- Log, 1937 (Box 107)
- Grower Log, 1902-1903 (Box 107)
- Experiment Log, 1896-1903 (Box 107)
- Vineyard Notes, 1942-1952 (Box 108)
- Record Books, 1892-1901 (Box 108)
- General Fruit Breeding Records, 1928-1936 (Box 109)
- Vineyard Notes, 1931-1935 (Box 109)
- Experiment Notepads, 1906-1914 (Box 109)
- Handwritten Papers and Drafts, Experiment Notepads, Correspondence, Books of Notes, 1900-1925 (Box 110)
- Fourth Annual Report, 1885 (Box 111, Folder 1)
- Fifth Annual Report-Seventh Annual Report, 1886-1888 (Box 111)
- Tenth Annual Report - Eighteenth Annual Report, 1891-1899 (Box 111)
- Nineteenth Annual Report - Thirtieth Annual Report, 1900-1911 (Box 112)
- Thirty-First Annual Report - Fortieth Annual Report, 1912-1921 (Box 113)
- Forty-Sixth Annual Report - Sixty-Third Annual Report, 1927-1944 (Box 113)
- One - Hundredth Annual Report, 1982 (Box 136, Folder 14)
- Progress Reports - Entomology, 1922-1952 (Box 114, Folder 1-29)
- Progress Reports - Entomology, 1953-1961 (Box 115, Folder 1-10)
- Project Abstracts - Entomology, 1961 (Box 115, Folder 11)
- Progress Reports - Entomology, 1962-1970 (Box 116, Folder 1-10)
- Budget Conference, 1969-1970 (Box 116, Folder 11)
- Progress Reports, Weeklies #5844 - #8443, July 1, 1943-June 30, 1954 (Box 117, Folder 1-11)
- Progress Reports, Weeklies #8444 - #9692, July 1, 1954-June 30, 1960 (Box 118, Folder 1-6)
- Day Book, 1934-1961 (Box 119)
- Cash Book, 1889-1923 (Box 119)
- Record Book, 1935-1943 (Box 119)
- 2 Notebooks, 1 Shorthand Notebook: Bulletins, Fruit Books, Funds on Hand (Box 119)
- 'The Geneva Times' Barton Lab Edition, May 19, 1969 (Box 119, Folder 4)
- "A Visit to The New York State Agricultural Experiment Station Geneva, New York" by Dr. Frank H. T. Rhodes, President, Cornell University, August 17, 1977 (Box 120)
- Pictorial Resume of the Fruit Project Subcommittee Meetings, September 25-26, 1963 (Box 120, Folder 2)
- Proclamation, New York State Wine Month, November, 1981 (Box 120, Folder 3)
- Resolution No.487, Assembly No.621; New York State Agricultural Experiment Station Week (Box 120, Folder 4)
- Resolution No. 192; Adopted February 1, 1983; Acknowledging Dr. Roelofs' Being Named Recipient of the 1982 Wolf Prize in Agriculture (Box 120, Folder 5)
- Eastern Regional Laboratories, 1952-1954 (Box 121, Folder 1)
- Estimated Funds by Source, 1977-1980 (Box 121, Folder 2)
- Financial Status Report, 1985 (Box 121, Folder 3)
- Northeastern Directors, 1942-1944 (Box 121, Folder 4)
- Northeastern Directors, 1944-1946 (Box 121, Folder 5)
- Northeastern Directors, 1947 (Box 121, Folder 6)
- Northeastern Directors, 1948 (Box 121, Folder 7)
- Northeastern Directors 3-1-E (Box 121, Folder 8)
- Northeastern Directors 3-1-F, 1950 (Box 121, Folder 9)
- Northeastern Directors 3-1-G, 1951 (Box 121, Folder 10)
- Northeastern Directors 3-1-G, 1952 (Box 121, Folder 11)
- Northeastern Directors, 1953 (Box 121, Folder 12)
- Northeastern-New Crops, June 1948-December 1948 (Box 121, Folder 13)
- Northeastern Regional Cooperative Research, New Crops, 1946-1947 (Box 121, Folder 14)
- Northeastern Regional Cooperative Research, New Crops, January 1948-June 1948 (Box 121, Folder 15)
- Northeastern Regional-New Crops, March 1, 1949-December 31, 1949 (Box 121, Folder 16)
- Northeastern Regional-New Crops, 1950 (Box 121, Folder 17)
- Northeastern Regional New-Crops, -- to March 1, 1969 (Box 121, Folder 18)
- Northeastern New Crops-Projects, 1948-1949 (Box 121, Folder 19)
- Plant Introductions-Stations (Box 121, Folder 20)
- Research Task Force Inter-Agency Committee; New England-New York (Box 121, Folder 21)
- Soil Conservation, 1939 (Box 121, Folder 22)
- Soil Conservation, 1940 (Box 121, Folder 23)
- Soil Conservation, 1941 (Box 121, Folder 24)
- Soil Conservation, 1942 (Box 121, Folder 25)
- Soil Conservation, 1943 (Box 121, Folder 26)
- Soil Conservation, 1944 (Box 121, Folder 27)
- Soil Conservation-Department Reports; Correspondence, 1946 (Box 121, Folder 28)
- Soil Conservation-Reports 3-11 (Box 121, Folder 29)
- USDA Regional Laboratories, 1942-1943 (Box 121, Folder 30)
- USDA Regional Laboratories, 1944-1945 (Box 121, Folder 31)
- USDA Regional Laboratories, 1946-1947 (Box 121, Folder 32)
- USDA Regional Laboratories, 1948-1949 (Box 121, Folder 33)
- USDA Regional Laboratories, 1950-1951 (Box 121, Folder 34)
- Weekly Reports of Geneva Project New York-R-4; C.S. Slater, Soil Technologist, 1938 (Box 121, Folder 35)
- Agreement between New York State Railways and New York State Agricultural Experiment Station, 1916 (Box 122, Folder 1)
- Bills, etc., Pertaining to Dairy and Bio Buildings (Box 122, Folder 2)
- Book Sales, 1949 (Box 122, Folder 3)
- Ceres Circle Program, 1954-1955 (Box 122, Folder 4)
- Certificate of Authority; Official Meteorological Observations, 1952-1953 (Box 122, Folder 5)
- Contracts, 1896-1909 (Box 122, Folder 6)
- Contracts, Johns-Manville Co. (Box 122, Folder 7)
- Contributions to Dahlia Collection (Box 122, Folder 8)
- Empire Gas and Electric Company (Box 122, Folder 9)
- Fertilizer Comparison of Analysis; Buffalo Goods (Box 122, Folder 10)
- Franked Envelopes Reports (Box 122, Folder 11)
- Information About Fertilizers (Box 122, Folder 12)
- Inventory Reports for Envelopes and Labels On Hand, June 30, 1948 (Box 122, Folder 13)
- Ledger, July 28, 1943-December 31, 1943 (Box 122, Folder 14)
- Ledger, January 2, 1944-December 30, 1944 (Box 122, Folder 15)
- Ledger, March 3, 1945-December 29, 1945 (Box 122, Folder 16)
- Ledger, January 2, 1946-December 31, 1946 (Box 122, Folder 17)
- Ledger, January 4, 1950-July 31, 1950 (Box 122, Folder 18)
- Ledger, January 4, 1951-December 31, 1951 (Box 122, Folder 19)
- Ledger, January 3, 1952-October 3, 1952 (Box 122, Folder 20)
- Ledger, January 6, 1952-December 31 (Box 122, Folder 21)
- Letter to General Curtiss Regarding Creation of An Agricultural Experiment Station in New York, 1880 (Box 122, Folder 22)
- Mail Inventory, April 5, 1954-July 1, 1954 (Box 122, Folder 23)
- Orchard and Vineyard Contracts (Box 122, Folder 24)
- Record Book-Apples of New York, 1913-1930; Cherries of New York, 1914-1927 (Box 122, Folder 28)
- Record Book-Bulletin Records, 1937(?)-1954 (Box 122, Folder 29)
- Record Book-Bulletins, 1937-1954; Loose Receipts (Box 122, Folder 30)
- Record Book-Cherries of New York, 1914-1937 (Box 122, Folder 31)
- Record Book-Edible Plants, 1919-1937 (Box 122, Folder 32)
- Record Book-Field Plots, Vol. II, 1882-1885 (Box 122, Folder 33)
- Record Book-Fruit and Vegetable, 1945-1954 (Box 122, Folder 34)
- Record Book-Fruit Books Sold, March 1, 1928-1937 (Box 122, Folder 35)
- Record Book-Peaches of New York, 1917-1937 (Box 122, Folder 36)
- Record Book-Pears of New York, 1923-1937 (Box 122, Folder 37)
- Record Book-Plums of New York, 1910-1935 (Box 122, Folder 38)
- Record Book-Small Fruits of New York, March 1926-1937 (Box 122, Folder 39)
- Record Book-Unit Cost of Bulletins, Technical Bulletins and Circulars (Box 122, Folder 40)
- Record Book-Various Expenses (no. 2), September 14, 1882-December 31, 1883 (Box 122, Folder 41)
- Referrals, January/March 1953-June 29, 1953 (Box 122, Folder 42)
- State Board of Charities (Box 122, Folder 43)
- Statements, October 2, 1944-April 2, 1953 (Box 122, Folder 44)
- Telephone Service Applications (Box 122, Folder 45)
- Committee of Nine Meeting, Geneva, New York, September 12-13, 1978 (Box 123, Folder 6)
- Heirloom Vegetable Garden (Box 123, Folder 7)
- Legislative Tour, 1968 (Box 123, Folder 8)
- MacAgrifacts (Box 123, Folder 10)
- New York State Fair, 1988 (Box 123, Folder 11)
- Northeastern Agricultural Experiment Station Directors, Summer Meeting, August 12-13, 1965 (Box 123, Folder 12)
- Open House, August 15, 1963 (Box 123, Folder 13)
- Open House, October 13, 1973 (Box 123, Folder 14)
- Open House, 1982 (Box 123, Folder 16)
- Plant Science Growth Facilities Study, August 28, 1981 (Box 123, Folder 18)
- State Fertility Meeting, 1964 (Box 123, Folder 19)
- Station History (Box 123, Folder 20)
- About Geneva (Box 124, Folder 1)
- Station History, 1942-1995 (Box 124, Folder 2A)
- Botanical Types-Fruits, Flowers, Stems (Box 124, Folder 3)
- Botany 8-Laboratory Notes (Box 124, Folder 4)
- Choke the Chokeberry Campaign; 1948-Mills, etc. (Box 124, Folder 5)
- Dilution Table-Dr. Mills, Papers by Mills and Burrell (Box 124, Folder 6)
- Direct and Indirect Effects of Lime Sulfur on Apple in Relation to Yield of Fruit (Box 124, Folder 7)
- Disease Discussion Outlines-Cornell (1) (Box 124, Folder 8)
- Disease Discussion Outlines-Cornell (2) (Box 124, Folder 9)
- Disease Mimeographs on Symptoms for Agents (Box 124, Folder 10)
- Diseases of Trees and Shrubs-Questionnaires (Box 124, Folder 11)
- Dusting of Apples and Peaches, H.W. Fitch, 1922 (Box 124, Folder 12)
- Extension bulletins, insect control guides, photos, 1954-1962 (Box 124, Folder 14)
- Federal Legislation, etc., Affecting State Agricultural Experiment Stations, 1954-1957 (Box 124, Folder 15)
- Fitch Table, 1924 (Box 124, Folder 16)
- Forms of Fruit-Drawings (Box 124, Folder 17)
- Fruit Dustings, 1920s (Box 124, Folder 18)
- Fruit Dusting Investigations, 1923-H.W. Fitch (Box 124, Folder 19)
- Fruit Dusting Investigations, 1924-H.W. Fitch (Box 124, Folder 20)
- Fruit Testing Cooperative, 1919-1984 (Box 124, Folder 21)
- New York State Fruit Testing Cooperative Association Meetings, 1956-1958,1961,1962 (Box 135, Folder 1-3)
- Agricultural Census Material and Questionnaire, 1959 (Box 135, Folder 6)
- Fruit Trees, Meetings, Lectures, 1957-1959 (Box 124, Folder 22)
- Fruits, Trees, Pests, Diseases, 1947-1958 (Box 124, Folder 23)
- Pictorial Resume of the Fruit Projects Subcommittee Meeting, September 23-26 1963 (Box 124, Folder 24)
- Pesticide Residue Work, 1951-1962 (Box 124, Folder 29)
- Questionnaire for Disease Specimens (Box 124, Folder 31)
- "Recommended Insecticides & Miticides" - Pennsylvania State Extension, 1957 (Box 124, Folder 32)
- "Recommended Fungicides & Nematocides" - Pennsylvania State Extension, 1963 (Box 124, Folder 33)
- Correspondence - George L. Slate, 1957-1967 (Box 124, Folder 35)
- Articles concerning statistics, 1946 (Box 124, Folder 36)
- Agriculture and Food Technology Park, 2002-06-28-2004-11-26 (Box 125, Folder 1)
- Board of Trustees: References to Geneva Experiment Station in Records of the Board of Trustees, 1926-1951 (Box 125, Folder 2)
- By-Laws of the Faculty of the New York State Agricultural Experiment Station, Adopted 19 October, 1982 (Box 125, Folder 4)
- Chairmen Meeting-Minutes, 1982-1988 (Box 125, Folder 5)
- Chairmen Meeting-Minutes, 1988-1990 (Box 125, Folder 6)
- Communication Services, 1971-05-10-1988-05 (Box 125, Folder 7)
- Communication Services - Research and Publications Lists, 1970-1991 (Box 136, Folder 13)
- Comprehensive Review-Vegetable Crops Research Program, 1957-1962 (Box 125, Folder 8)
- Comprehensive Review-Vegetable Crops, 1968 (Box 125, Folder 9)
- Comprehensive Review-Vegetable Crops and Seed and Vegetable Sciences, Geneva, 1977-1982 (Box 125, Folder 10)
- Geneva Seed Testing Laboratory, no date (Box 136, Folder 8)
- Vegetable Crops Research, 1935-1982 (Box 136, Folder 9)
- Cornell Pomology Club, 1976,1980 (Box 125, Folder 11)
- Directory of Seed Pathologists in the Americas, 1978-08 (Box 125, Folder 12)
- Facts on the Use of Pesticides (Box 125, Folder 20)
- Food Science Programs, Department of Food Science, Cornell University (Ithaca), 1986 (Box 125, Folder 21)
- Food Science Programs, Institute of Food Science, 1986 (Box 125, Folder 22)
- Food Science Technology at Geneva, New York, 1963, 1982-1986 (Box 125, Folder 23)
- Food Science and Technology, 1994 (Box 125, Folder 24)
- Fruit Varieties (Box 125, Folder 25)
- Geneva Plan for Fruit and Vegetable Research (Box 125, Folder 26)
- Grape Research Communications (Box 125, Folder 27)
- U.P. Hedrick, Essays from Proceedings of the New York State Historical Society, 1927-1932 (Box 125, Folder 28)
- History of Horticulture at the Agricultural Experiment Station (Box 125, Folder 30)
- Horticultural Sciences Program/Budget Conference, 2001-2002 (Box 135, Folder 4)
- USDA Grape Genetics Research Unit - Grape Germplasm Repository List and Event Program, 2008 (Box 135, Folder 7)
- Heritage Grape Varieties - Block Map, 2008 (Box 135, Folder 8)
- W.H. Jordan, Essays from Proceedings of Western New York Horticultural Society, 1908, 1911 (Box 125, Folder 31)
- Kanadesaga-Iroquois/British Settlement in Western New York State (Box 125, Folder 32)
- Pesticide Control Board Meeting, 1965-09-15 (Box 125, Folder 33)
- Robert A. Plane, Director, Correspondence (Box 125, Folder 37)
- Pomology Study Manuals, 1977-1979 (Box 125, Folder 38)
- Report, Committee to Study New York State Agricultural Experiment Station, Geneva, New York, 1966-04 (Box 125, Folder 39)
- Research Projects and Investigations in Entomology and Plant Pathology, 1969-05 (Box 125, Folder 40)
- Plant Pathology Reports, 1980-1989 (Box 136, Folder 15)
- Dr. Wendell L. Roelofs, Alexander von Humboldt Foundation Award, 1977-05-19 (Box 125, Folder 42)
- Robert S. Shallenberger, Correspondence, Parrott Hall (Box 125, Folder 43)
- Advisory Council, 1970 (Box 126, Folder 1)
- Catalog-New and Noteworthy Fruits, 1979-1980 (Box 126, Folder 2)
- Catalogs-Spraying Machines (Box 126, Folder 3)
- Development of Improved Practices in Marketing Apples, Correspondence, 1956 (Box 126, Folder 6)
- Employee Day, 1982-07-16 (Box 126, Folder 7)
- Handling Methods and Costs of Storing and Packing Apples-Reports, 1956 (Box 126, Folder 9)
- Handling Methods and Costs in Storing and Packing Apples, 1959 (Box 126, Folder 10)
- Apple Varieties Grown at NYSAES, 1959 (Box 136, Folder 10)
- Hudson Valley Laboratory Brochure, 1959 (Box 126, Folder 11)
- Hudson Valley Laboratory, 50th Anniversary Celebration, 1973-08-02-1973-08-03 (Box 126, Folder 12)
- Hudson Valley Open House, 1964 (Box 126, Folder 13)
- Inter-Regional Research Projects, 1951 (Box 126, Folder 14-15)
- Minutes of Meetings of Technical Advising Commission of Regional Fruit Marketing Project, 1947-1959 (Box 126, Folder 16-17)
- Plant Introductions and Inventories, New Crops, 1948-1953 (Box 126, Folder 18-19)
- Press Kit for "Press Day", 1969-03-25 (Box 126, Folder 20)
- Proposed Project to Replace NEM-19, 1959 (Box 126, Folder 22)
- Rate of Movement of Apples (USDA Market News Leased Wire System), 1957 (Box 126, Folder 23)
- Repository, Information, Germplasm (Box 126, Folder 24)
- Special Section, Geneva Times, May 19,1969 (Box 126, Folder 25)
- State Fertility Meet, July 16-17, 1964 (Box 126, Folder 26)
- Tour and Brochure, January 10, 1966 (Box 126, Folder 27)